<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<root>
    <entries date="1858-08-24">
        <heading>August 24.</heading>

        <message><message_info sender="Valentia">Valentia to Newfoundland.</message_info> “The
            Lord-Mayor of London to the Hon. Daniel F. Tiemann, Mayor of New York:—The Lord Mayor of
            London most cordially reciprocates congratulations of Mayor New York upon the success of
            so important an undertaking as the completion of the Atlantic Telegraph Cable. It is
            indeed one of the most glorious triumphs of the age, and reflects the highest credit
            upon the energy, skill, and perseverance of all parties intrusted with so difficult a
            duty; and the Lord Mayor sincerely trusts, that, by the blessing of Almighty God, it may
            be the means of reuniting those kind feelings that now exist between the two countries.
            “ R. W. GARDEN, Lord Mayor.”</message>

        <message><message_info sender="Newfoundland">Newfoundland to Valentia.</message_info>
            “Repeat between ’duty’and ’sincerely.’” “Message all right,—understood.”</message>

        <message><message_info sender="Valentia">Valentia to Newfoundland.</message_info> “Thomson
            to De Sauty:—On what instrument do you receive? How many divisions deflection do you
            get? What battery? How many cells? What key? Directors desire you send news, public
            interest, but none commercial. Have you any now?” “Can you take a long
            message?”</message>

        <message><message_info sender="Newfoundland">Newfoundland to Valentia.</message_info> “Go
            on.”</message>

        <message><message_info sender="Valentia">Valentia to Newfoundland.</message_info> “Saward to
            De Sauty:—Answer by telegraph what length shore-end you require, and if any small cable
            as a reserve. How much surplus had Niagara, and where is it? Have you splices and
            jointers enough? We have chartered the Bilboa to lay the end. Telegraph full
            particulars, and if you require anything beside gutta-percha articles I will send them
            by the Bilboa.</message>

        <message><message_info sender="Newfoundland">Newfoundland to Valentia.</message_info>
            “Repeat from ‘shore-end’to ‘small.’” “Acknowledged Saward to De Sauty.”</message>

        <message><message_info sender="Valentia">Valentia to Newfoundland.</message_info> "C.W.
            Field:—We desire you to place in America about £ 15,000 unappropriated £20 shares,
            authorized February last- Reply by telegraph. Soonest. C.M. SAMPSON.”</message>

        <message><message_info sender="Newfoundland">Newfoundland to Valentia</message_info>
            “Acknowledged message.”</message>

        <message><message_info sender="Valentia">Valentia to Newfoundland.</message_info> “Answer
            each question about instruments.” (Refers to Thomson’s message.) “Your currents vary
            much. Very weak to-day. How ours to-day?” (This is in answer to Newfoundland’s attempt
            to send message.)</message>

        <message><message_info sender="Newfoundland">Newfoundland to Valentia.</message_info> “To
            Thomson:—Receiving on your galvanometer, thirty divisions. Galvanometer seven degrees.
            Print local circuit by hand. The large Smee’s. Whitehouse’s reversing key. News Persia.
            DE SAUTY.” “Have you received message right? Service for Saward. Will you take
            it?”</message>

        <message><message_info sender="Valentia">Valentia to Newfoundland.</message_info> “Yes; and
            prepare after to receive Thomson’s compensated currents.”</message>

        <message><message_info sender="Newfoundland">Newfoundland to Valentia.</message_info> “De
            Sauty to Saward:—Two miles shore-end ample. Have half-mile small cable; plenty. It is
            stowed on beach. Two splicers and jointer here. Six gallons naphtha required. Please
            send authority to draw on Brooking. £100 required immediately for laborer’s house in a
            wilderness. Roads to make and woods to cut down and clear. Ought to have some more
            relays. Have only one great difficulty in sending letters from here. Have written
            fully.”</message>

        <message><message_info sender="Valentia">Valentia to Newfoundland.</message_info>
            “Understand. Give news of Persia. Also public news for morning papers. Send much
            faster.”</message>
    </entries>
</root>
